MAICOL FELIPE DUQUE URREA

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

+7 years of experience as a Software Engineer. High sense of belonging, good dynamism and personal improvement aspirations, team work ability. Passionate problem solver, keep up with the latest technologies and development methods, constantly expanding my skills as a self-taught learner. Javascript lover and its entire ecosystem. I've worked with NodeJS, React, Angular and Vue. Ability to analyze and face challenges that seek improvement through IT solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Developer at Qrvey S.A.S

March 2021 - Present · [Medellín, Colombia] [Analytics platform for SaaS companies]

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Development of v2 of the report builder from scratch, improving the architectural problems of the v1 using best practices and SOLID principles.
- Mentoring junior developers joining the team.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Helped other teams to implement E2E testing in their projects by mentoring and talking about Cypress.
- Contributed to improve product quality by implementing E2E testing using Cypress.
- Contributed to create a better and more efficient product.

Frontend Developer at I.A.S Ingeniería, Aplicaciones y Software S.A.S

March 2019 - March 2021 · 2 yrs [Medellín, Colombia] [Develop software solutions company]

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Developed web application using React and NextJS.
- Design and development of the frontend side of the module that allows making claims to end users through the web platform.
- Built platform to allow health professionals such as psychologists and therapists to offer their services through the platform.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Helped users to make their insurance claims much easier, saving a lot of time and avoiding processes.
- Became frontend lead for the project. I had to design the frontend architecture.

Software Developer at Canal Virtual S.A.S

April 2015 - March 2019 · 2 yrs [Medellín, Colombia] [Educational marketing company]

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Developed and designed new features for the platform.
- Developed statistics and gamification module.
- Supported and improved legacy modules.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Implemented new features using NodeJS.
- Built real time chat with NodeJS and web sockets.

SKILLS

- Problem solving
- Team player
- Fast learner
- Agile principles
- Mentoring
- Active listening
- Git
- NodeJS

- JavaScript
- React
- NextJS
- Angular

EDUCATION

Software Engineer at Politécnico Colombiano Jaime Isaza Cadavid

March 2021 - [Medellín, Colombia]

LANGUAGES

Spanish and English.